[rock music playing]
‎（威斯康辛州 点域镇）
‎（1995年7月3日）
‎（上午11:47）
[rock drumbeat playing]
‎（地点）
‎（凯蒂福尔曼家厨房）
-["Groove is in the Heart" intro plays]
-We're going to sing and have some fun…
["Groove is in the Heart"
by Deee-Lite playing]
♪ Groove is in the heart ♪
‎铭刻在心…
♪ Grooving in the heart ♪
‎你好香
You smell good.
‎是蛋黄酱香
Oh, it is the Hellmann's.
[car door shuts]
‎是车门声吗？
Was that a car door?
-[music stops]
-[car door shuts]
‎是车门声 我去
That was a car door. I got it. I got it!
‎我去
I got it! I got it!
I got it! I got it! I got it!
‎我的天啊 妈妈 我都还没敲门
Oh my God. Mom, I didn't even knock.
[chuckles]
[Kitty coos]
‎妈
Mom.
‎妈妈 你蹭我胸了
Mom, you're motorboating me.
‎爸
Dad.
‎-儿子
‎-抱一个？
Son.
‎-儿子
‎-抱一个？
Hug?
‎-算了
[both] Nah.
‎奶奶 爷爷 你们好
Hey, Grandma. Hey, Grandpa.
‎莉亚 我的孙女
Leia. My grandbaby.
‎嘿 孩子 你可真是长高了
Hey, kiddo.
Boy, you sure have gotten tall.
‎而且胸花怒放了 恭喜
Oh, and congratulations.
Those buds are blooming.
‎您…气色也不赖？
Yours… look good too?
‎我敢说你在篮球场上肯定彪悍得很
Why, I bet you're a holy terror
on the basketball court.
‎我听说你有你妈妈的跳投绝活
‎还有你爸爸的…姓
I hear you got your mom's jump shot
and your dad's
‎我听说你有你妈妈的跳投绝活
‎还有你爸爸的…姓
last name.
‎-我去下洗手间
‎-喂
-I'm gonna take a bathroom break.
-Hey, hey, hey.
‎拧水龙头要小心 出水烫死人
Just be careful with the faucets.
The water comes out, like, scalding hot.
‎艾瑞克 水是正常温度
It's a normal temperature, Eric.
‎是你小子皮太嫩
You've just got that sensitive baby skin.
‎要知道
You know,
‎我很期待今年独立日的周末
I am so excited
about this Fourth of July weekend.
‎大家一起烤香肠 看焰火…
We are gonna grill weenies,
watch the fireworks…
‎我还租了《小美人鱼》
I even rented The Little Mermaid.
‎谢谢妈妈 但她已经不喜欢这个了
Oh. Thanks, Mom,
but she's not really into that anymore.
‎我们的小美人鱼…来月经了
Our little mermaid… got her period.
‎老天 艾瑞克
-[Kitty gasps]
-God, Eric!
[thudding]
‎别担心 亲爱的 我能搞定
Don't worry, honey. I got it.
[rock music playing]
‎（90年代秀）
‎你好 威斯康辛！
[young woman] Hello, Wisconsin!
‎谁想来块热乎乎的肉桂甜饼？
Who wants a warm snickerdoodle?
‎我要 妈 闻头发有点诡异哈
I do. It's a little weird
that you're smelling my hair, Mom.
‎圣诞节过后 我就没见过你了
‎所以我想怎么闻就怎么闻
I haven't seen you since Christmas,
so I will smell you however I want,
‎你不准反抗
and you're fine with it.
‎对了 唐娜
‎艾瑞克把你新书的评论寄给我们了
So, Donna, Eric sent us
the review of your new book.
‎我们看了哦
We read it.
‎你们看我新书了？
Oh, you read my book?
‎没有 看的是书评
No, the review.
‎谢了 福婶
Thanks, Mrs. F.
Aww…
‎-我希望你叫“妈” 知道吗？
‎-知道
-I wish you'd call me Mom, you know?
-I know.
‎好吧
Okay.
‎有朝一日吧
Someday.
‎就这周末
This weekend.
‎艾瑞克 大学里的工作怎么样？
So, Eric, how are things
at the university?
‎挺好的 我现在是客座教授了
Going great. I'm an adjunct professor now,
‎也就有了永久停车位
which means I got
a permanent parking space
‎放我的自行车
for my bicycle.
‎老爸 课程受欢迎就会这样
That's what happens
when your course is super popular, Dad.
‎“《星球大战》的宗教”哇？
"The Religion of Star Wars"?
‎是的
Oh yeah.
‎下回打仗 这个国家输定了
This country's gonna lose the next war.
‎如果是星际善恶争霸就不会
Not if it's an intergalactic battle
between good and evil.
‎嘿 我去打一会篮球
Hey, I'm gonna go shoot some hoops.
‎跟爷爷奶奶说说 咱们暑假要做什么
Hey, Leia, tell your grandparents
what we're doing this summer.
‎我们要去…
Oh, we're going to--
‎阿拉巴马州的亨茨维尔
‎参加父女太空营
We're going to Huntsville, Alabama,
for a little father-daughter Space Camp.
‎就我俩…足足俩礼拜
Just the two of us… for two weeks.
‎休斯顿 请求玩耍 完毕
[imitates radio static]
Houston, permission to have fun, over.
‎休斯顿 能收到吗？完毕
[imitates static]
Houston, do you read me, over?
‎-准许玩耍
‎-对啦
-[imitates static] Permission granted.
-[laughs] Yeah!
‎但你…没有说“完毕”
But you… you didn't say "over."
‎-妈妈
‎-好了 莉亚 去投篮吧
-Mom?
-Okay, Leia, go shoot some baskets.
‎你爸越呆越来劲 你还是别看为好
I don't need you
to see your dad get any nerdier.
‎太空营
Space Camp.
‎你要打扮成巴克罗杰斯吗？
Do you get to put on
a Buck Rogers costume?
‎不会 那得购买指令舱体验
Nah. Only if you buy
the Command Module experience.
‎其实我买了
[whispers] Which I did!
‎莉亚好像不太想去
Leia doesn't seem like she wants to go.
‎感觉她这个年纪应该需要空间
I think she might be
at that age where she needs space.
‎我有给她空间…太空营
I'm giving her space… camp.
‎-太空营
‎-艾瑞克和莉亚最近有点磕绊
-Space Camp.
-Eric's having a hard time with Leia.
‎38岁…是个坎儿
It's a tough age… 38.
‎好吧
Okay. Okay.
‎我只知道无论怎样
‎我都会爱她 在她身后支持她
All I know is that I'm going to love her
and stand behind her, no matter what.
‎这主意不错
That is a great idea.
‎因为站在他们身后 就更方便…
Because when you stand
behind your kids, it's easier--
‎打他们屁股
[all] To put your foot in their ass.
‎明白 老爸 谢了
We got it, Dad. Thanks.
[hip-hop beat playing]
[young woman] ♪ And I'm here ♪
♪ To remind you ♪
♪ Of the mess you left
When you went away ♪
♪ It's not fair ♪
♪ To deny me ♪
♪ Of the cross I bear
That you gave to me ♪
♪ You, you, you oughta know! ♪
‎你好
Hello.
‎你在干嘛 变态？
What are you doing, creeper?
‎没做什么怪事 我只是站在你窗外
Oh, nothing weird! [laughs]
I was just standing outside your window
and watching you sing
‎看着你唱歌 想象着当你是什么感觉
and wondering
what it would be like to… be you.
‎我走了
I'll go now. [gasps]
‎除非你想听我从芝加哥搞到的盗版带
Unless you want to hear
a cool bootleg I got in Chicago.
‎接着说
Oh, I'm listening.
‎嗯 可牛了
Yeah, it's, uh, pretty major.
‎超牛的盗版
Big-time bootleg.
‎盗版得不行
The bootiest of legs.
‎赶紧去拿就对了
Just go get it.
‎马上
On it.
‎等我回来时 你一定要在啊
Please be here when I get back.
["Sad Tomorrow" by The Muffs playing]
‎这是你妈妈以前的房间
‎而你爸就住在隔壁？
So this was your mom's old room,
and your dad lived next door?
‎我敢说他们经常在这里打炮
I bet they boned in here all the time.
‎这下就明白多了
Explains a lot.
‎有时
Sometimes,
‎在深夜
late at night,
‎周围一片寂静的时候
when everything's quiet,
‎我依然能听到…
I can still hear the…
[imitates mattress creaking]
‎抱歉 我喜欢让人不舒服
Sorry. I love making people
feel uncomfortable.
‎你挺厉害的
You're really good at it. [scoffs]
‎总之 给我讲讲芝加哥的事
‎你有什么爱好？
Anyway, tell me about Chicago.
What are you into?
‎我？多了去了
Me? Uh, a lot of stuff.
‎上学
School.
‎可喜欢上学了
School's a big one.
‎我在辩论俱乐部是个大人物
‎这点不容争辩
And I'm a pretty big deal in Debate Club.
‎我在辩论俱乐部是个大人物
‎这点不容争辩
That's not up for debate. [chuckles]
‎好吧 我没人气
Yeah, I'm not popular.
‎很好
Good.
‎有人气的都是衰人
Popular people suck.
‎没错 衰得很
Yeah, they really do.
‎这段可赞了
Ooh, this part's dope.
[volume increases]
‎见鬼 格温！
Damn it, Gwen!
‎把这破玩意关小点 人家正剃毛呢
Turn that crap down. I'm trying to shave.
‎我老哥 不是一个爸生的 他还行
Older brother. Different dads. He's cool.
‎主要是他有辆面包车 还好欺负
Mostly 'cause he has a van,
and he's fun to mess with.
‎看好了
-Watch this.
-[volume increases]
‎说真的 格温 我差点把奶头剃了
Seriously, Gwen. I almost nicked my nerps.
‎这叽叽歪歪的娘娘腔调 我越听越毛
This whiny vagina music is bumming me out!
‎是吗 内特？
-[music stops]
-Oh yeah, Nate?
‎我和我朋友要组建一支乐队
‎就叫“叽歪娘娘”
Me and my new friend are gonna
start a band and call it Whiny Vagina.
‎那我也组个乐队 就叫“这名真傻缺”
I'm gonna start a band
and call it That's Stupid.
‎不赖
Nice.
[music resumes loudly]
‎该死 格温！
[Nate] Damn it, Gwen!
‎我就喜欢家里都是人
I love having the house full again.
‎感觉…让我充满快乐
It just… It fills me with joy.
‎等你走了 我就伤心了
And then you leave, and it's sad.
‎然后 冬天就来了
And then winter comes.
‎然后我去给妈妈上坟
And I visit Mom's grave.
‎我给她讲家里满是亲人有多开心
And I tell her how much fun it was
when the house was full.
‎-现在能把糖浆给我吗？
‎-当然
-So can I have the syrup now?
-Oh, of course.
‎早安 拜拜
Morning. Bye.
‎我说 你鼻子里那是什么玩意儿？
Whoa. What the hell is that thing
in your nose?
‎鼻环？
Uh, a nose ring?
‎看你的了 嫩皮娃娃
Your move, baby skin.
‎-怎么会这样？
‎-是格温给我的
-How did this happen?
-Gwen gave it to me.
‎是格温啊 好吧 我不知道是她
Oh! Okay, it was Gwen.
Cool. I didn't know it was Gwen.
‎你离开之前 我有个问题
Question before you leave.
‎格温是谁啊 她干嘛在你脸上戳洞？
Who is Gwen, and why is she
poking holes in your perfect face?
‎她住在隔壁 我现在正要去那里
She lives next door,
which is where I'm going right now.
‎-她父母在家吗？
‎-不 她哥哥在
-Are her parents home?
-No, but her older brother is.
‎亲 你是在给自己挖坑
Honey, you're really
not helping your case.
‎老爸 我离家也就六米远
Dad, I'll be 20 feet away.
‎好吧 但你要赶回来看焰火
Okay, you can go, but you have to be
home in time for fireworks.
‎-好吗？
‎-我尽量
-Okay?
-I'll try.
Ah, ah, ah, ah!
‎正如尤达大师所说…
As Master Yoda said--
‎干嘛呀？
-Why?
-[Red grumbles]
‎正如尤达大师所说：
‎“做或不做 没有尽量”
As Master Yoda said,
"Do or do not. There is no try."
‎尤达大师是虚假世界里
‎一个被打了屁股的小人儿
Master Yoda was a puppet from a fake
world with some guy's hand up his butt.
‎你就是故意说难听话
Now you're just being hurtful.
‎十几岁的娃娃最难搞
Ah, teenagers!
‎儿子 我同情你
I feel for you, son.
‎不过话说回来
But, on the other hand,
‎出来混 迟早要还的
payback's a bitch.
[rock music playing]
‎乌诺
Uno.
‎你好像只能放一张牌
I think you're only allowed
to drop one card.
‎什么？
Excuse me?
‎地下室真不赖
Cool basement.
‎这里就是垃圾场
It's a dump.
‎无意冒犯
No offense.
‎奥兹和我是去年留堂时认识的
Ozzie and I met last year in detention.
‎跟她说说你干了啥
Tell her what you did.
‎我跟我的数学老师说他老婆出轨
I told my math teacher
his wife was cheating on him.
‎她跟别的汉子在“国际松饼之家”亲热
She was making out with some dude at IHOP.
‎-太可怕了
‎-就是
-That's horrible.
-[Ozzie] I know.
‎“国际松饼之家” 拜托有点档次
IHOP.
Show some class.
[running footsteps]
‎你们肯定不信 我遇上的事赞爆了
You're not gonna believe what happened.
It's the best thing ever!
‎烤制猪排堡回归的时候 你也这么说
That's what you said
when the McRib came back.
‎妮可 我还以为再也吃不着了呢
I thought it was gone forever, Nik.
‎你害怕了？
Aww! You were scared?
‎哦 宝贝
Oh, babe.
‎嘿 新来的妹子
Hey, new girl.
‎嘿 小子
Hey, boy. [chuckles]
‎小伙子？
Man…?
‎我不知道你青春期过得咋样
‎应该不赖吧
I don't know how
the whole puberty thing is going for you.
‎我不知道你青春期过得咋样
‎应该不赖吧
Probably great. [chuckles]
‎莉亚 他叫杰伊
Leia, this is Jay.
‎记得把你的拉链和扣子都系好拉上
Please place all your zippers and buttons
in their upright and locked positions.
‎别这样 格温 我就是聊聊 交交心
Hey, not cool, Gwen. I'm just doing
a little get-to-know-you chitchat.
‎说起来
So,
‎你崇尚精神吗？
are you spiritual?
‎反正我崇尚
I am.
‎你又是那副样子
You're making a face.
‎但这招对我挺管用
But that would have worked on me.
‎我能讲我的精彩遭遇了吗？
Can I tell my awesome story now?
‎我们就在我车里待着
So we were just chilling in my van.
‎-为什么他总是坐在前面？
‎-因为我抢到了副驾
-Why does he always get to sit in front?
-I called shotgun.
‎-我可是你女朋友
‎-没错 但他是我最好的朋友
-But I'm your girlfriend.
-Yeah, but he's my best friend.
‎-兄弟
-Bro.
‎兄弟
Bro.
‎老天 我居然为你拒绝了学长
Oh my God. I turned down a senior for you.
‎对不住 宝贝 但你们俩对我都很重要
I'm sorry, babe,
but you're both important to me.
‎12年来 杰伊都是我的后援
But Jay's had my back
for the past 12 years,
‎而过去六个月 我的前庭都是你的
‎手心手背都是肉
and you've had my front
for the last six months. I can't choose.
‎喂 你们是来取
‎“老妈折扣酒铺”的酒桶的吗？
Hey. Are you here to pick up the keg
from Mama's Discount Liquors?
‎-没错
-Yes.
‎而且你们预付了 对吧？
And you prepaid, right?
‎-是的
-Yes.
‎好得很
Sweet.
‎独立日愉快
Happy Fourth.
‎-兄弟！
-Bro!
‎-兄弟
-Bro.
-Bro. Bro!
‎-兄弟
-Bro!
-Bro.
‎-兄弟
‎他俩一路上就这样
They were like this the whole ride.
‎拜托 宝贝 这可是独立日的奇迹
Come on, babe.
It's a Fourth of July miracle.
‎而且还有啤酒
With beer!
‎还在这里废话什么？
‎咱们一起喝他个烂醉如泥
Why are we still talking?
Let's tap that keg and get stupid!
‎-对
‎-坏了
-Yeah.
-Oh no.
‎我们没有酒头
We don't have a tap.
‎没有酒头的话 啤酒就…出不来
And, without a tap,
the beer is… is trapped.
‎-亲一下感觉会好点吗？
‎-除非你嘴里全是啤酒
-Would a kiss make it better?
-Not unless you have a mouth full of beer.
‎-是吗？
‎-不是
-Do you?
-No, I don't.
[rock music playing]
‎这感觉好奇怪
This feels weird.
‎很不一样
Very different.
‎我反正挺高兴的
Well, I'm having fun.
‎怎么烟熏火燎的？
Why is it so smoky?
‎天啊 爆米花
Oh God, the popcorn!
‎孩子们 玩得开心吗？
Enjoying yourselves, kids?
‎你们现在也在楼上耍了
You're upstairs people now.
‎我就知道会这样
I knew it would happen.
‎只是没想到这么快
Just not this soon.
‎别担心了 艾瑞克 莉亚不会有事的
Quit worrying, Eric. Leia will be fine.
‎你现在能预知未来了吗？
So now you can tell the future?
‎我买那双滑溜溜的棕色鞋子时
‎你在哪里呢？
Where were you when I bought
those slippery brown shoes?
‎-我连机场的坡道都上不去
‎-好了 艾瑞克
I couldn't get up the ramp at the airport.
‎-我连机场的坡道都上不去
‎-好了 艾瑞克
[Donna] Okay, Eric.
‎不给你喝果酒了
No more Zima for you.
‎你说得对 我都喝飘了
Yeah, you're right. I'm… I'm flying.
‎多数爆米花都还好
I saved most of it.
‎谢谢 妈妈
Ah. Thanks, Mom.
‎“妈妈”
"Mom."
‎看到没 多好叫啊 唐娜？
You see how easy it is, Donna?
‎叫一声不就完了？
Can't you just say it?
‎不要 感觉像被迫的
Nah. Feels forced.
‎拜托 妈妈 别纠结了
Come on, Mom, just drop it.
‎不要 感觉像被迫的
Nah.
Feels forced.
[rock music playing]
‎小屁孩对阵啤酒
Kids versus beer.
‎一个亘古不变的传说
It's a tale as old as time.
‎父母 祖辈 无不如此
It happened to our parents
and our parents' parents.
‎“五月花号”上的孩子们
The kids on the Mayflower.
‎奥兹 你好烦 我正想办法呢
Ozzie. You're killing me, man.
I'm trying to think here.
‎我知道 闻得出来
I know. I can smell it.
‎等等 为什么不回“老妈”那里
‎去买酒头呢？
Wait, why can't we just
go back to Mama's and get a tap?
‎我们都试过去她家买酒 但她很难搞
We've all tried to buy from her,
but she's tough.
‎我还试着跟她搭讪说：
I mean, I even hit her with the,
‎“嘿 妹子”
"Hey, girl."
‎啥用都没有
Nothing.
‎-如果我们用激光呢？
‎-我们没有激光
-What if we get a laser?
-We're not getting a laser.
‎那就这样了 能试的都试了
Well, I guess that's it.
We tried everything.
‎你就说了一个主意 还蠢得要命
You said one idea, and it was stupid.
‎你才蠢
You're stupid!
‎你们都蠢 你们讨厌啤酒 讨厌美国
You're all stupid!
You hate beer and you hate America.
‎-宝贝？
‎-嗯？
-Baby?
-Yeah?
‎你是不是很沮丧？
Are you feeling frustrated?
‎嗯
Yeah.
‎-所以你就跟别人发脾气？
‎-嗯
-Is this why you're lashing out at others?
-Yeah.
‎咱们明天进小树林
‎我看你对着树打空手道怎么样？
How about tomorrow we go into the woods,
and I watch you do karate on a tree?
‎好得很
-I'd really like that.
-Oh.
‎你们这些笨蛋闹够了没？
Are you dill weeds finished?
‎莉亚 你去买 老妈还不认识你
Leia, you should buy the tap.
Mama doesn't know you.
‎对啊 你肯定能行
Oh yeah. You totally could.
‎再说 你眼睛美得要命
‎虽然买酒头用不上
Plus, your eyes are crazy pretty,
which won't really help get the tap,
‎但我还是注意到了
but it's something I noticed.
‎嘿 妹子
-Hey, girl.
-[scoffs]
‎莉亚 这可屌爆了
Leia, it would be so badass.
‎我也做过一些疯狂的事
I guess I have done
some pretty crazy things.
‎一次在海边
‎一只海鸥偷了我的三明治
One time at the beach,
a seagull stole my sandwich,
‎我小声骂她“贱货”
and, under my breath,
I… called her "bitch."
‎你们猜怎么的？我去
You know what? I'm in.
‎好得很 新妹子真牛
All right. New girl is sick.
‎-上车
‎-稍等
-To the van!
-Pause.
‎这样行不通
This isn't gonna work.
‎见到这童装女
‎人家肯定要看她身份证
I'm pretty sure OshKosh B'gosh here
is gonna get carded.
‎有道理
Good point.
‎我有个主意
I have an idea.
‎亲 你都这样了 确定要喝酒吗？
You sure you want to be drinking
in your condition, hon?
‎我是给我老公的买的
‎酒桶是给宝宝派对准备的
Oh, it's… [nervous chuckle]
‎我是给我老公的买的
‎酒桶是给宝宝派对准备的
It's for my husband.
He… He got a keg for the baby shower.
‎好高级
Oh, fancy.
[register beeping]
‎-一共39块5
‎-好的
-That'll be $39.50.
-Okay.
‎我不是什么妇科大夫
‎但你这肚子瞅着不对劲
I'm no lady doctor, but I think
something's wrong with the baby.
‎想得美
Nice try.
‎真受够你们这帮小屁孩了
‎我这就报警
I'm sick of you kids.
I'm calling the cops.
‎老妈 把电话放下
Put the phone down, Mama.
‎闭嘴
Shut up.
‎好吧 等警察来了
Fine, but when the cops get here,
‎你要怎么跟他们解释
‎为什么你把一桶酒给了一群孩子？
how are you gonna explain to them
why you gave a keg to a bunch of kids?
‎不是我 是韦德干的
It wasn't me. It was Wade.
‎老妈
Mama!
‎无论如何 你都会被吊销卖酒执照
Either way, you lose your liquor license.
‎所以把电话放下 把酒头卖给我
‎大家高高兴兴过个独立日
So put the phone down, sell me the tap,
and we all have a nice Fourth of July.
‎你是干嘛的 当律师吗？
What are you, some sort of lawyer?
‎辩论俱乐部 初中地区赛第一名
Debate Club.
First place, junior regionals.
‎你根本不是我的对手
It was over before it started.
[gasps]
[rock music playing]
‎敬老妈克星 莉亚！
To Leia, the Mama slayer!
‎敬莉亚！
[all] To Leia!
‎也敬扎波尔斯基老师
And to Mrs. Zapolski. [chuckles]
‎我在辩论俱乐部的教练
‎每天逼着我练
My Debate Club coach,
for pushing me so damn hard.
‎敬扎波尔斯基老师！
[all] To Mrs. Zapolski!
‎快看 妮可 是流星 快许愿
Wow. Look, Nik, a shooting star.
Make a wish.
‎亲 那是焰火表演
That's a firework, babe.
[fireworks whistling and popping]
‎天啊 你今晚真是太牛了
‎没想到你还有这一面
Man, you were such a badass tonight.
I didn't know you had it in you.
‎我也没想到 但我喜欢这种感觉
Neither did I, but I love this feeling.
‎感觉很自由 很开心
‎真希望我能留在这里过暑假
I feel free and happy.
Wish I could stay for the summer.
‎那就留下吧
Then stay.
‎我爸不会同意的
[snickers] My dad will never let me.
‎我爸妈离婚的时候
When my parents split up,
‎学校的心理医生说我会丧一辈子
the school shrink basically told me
that everything was gonna suck forever,
‎我心想：“我才不要”
and I was like, "Nope. Not this girl."
‎于是我回到家
‎在洗衣机顶上漂了头发
So I went home, bleached my hair
over the washing machine,
‎剪开牛仔裤 下定决心 这是我的人生
cut up my jeans
and decided that this is my life,
‎我绝对不会丧下去
and it's never gonna suck.
‎这话听起来有点傻
This is gonna sound so dorky,
‎但是…我有点想跟你成为好友
but… I'm interested in
us becoming best friends,
‎我该怎么做呢？
so how do we make that happen?
‎留下来过暑假
Stay for the summer.
‎你也用不着傻话免责声明
‎已经暗含了
And you can drop the dorky disclaimer.
It's implied.
[chuckles]
‎好得很
Oh great.
‎她错过了焰火表演和香肠
Now she's missed the fireworks
and the weenies.
‎它们冷冰冰皱巴巴躺在盘子里
‎就像我的心一样
Now they're sitting on a plate
all cold and shriveled just like my heart.
‎艾瑞克
Oh, Eric.
‎妈 闻头发还是很诡异
The hair thing,
it's still a little weird, Mom.
‎最糟糕的是什么？
‎我该珍惜与莉亚共度的时光
Know what the worst part is?
I should be treasuring time with Leia.
‎结果我…却巴不得这段时光赶紧结束
Instead, I mean,
I… can't wait for it to end.
‎亲爱的 等你死了就结束了
Oh, sweetie.
It ends when you die.
‎莉亚塔图因福尔曼
Leia Tatooine Forman.
‎-她的中间名是安妮
‎-我可没答应
-Her middle name is Anne.
-Know what? I never agreed to that.
‎你去哪里了？
‎我的天啊 那是啤酒吗？
Where have you been?
Oh my God. Is that beer?
‎是的 从水塔下来时
‎把杯里剩下的全给洒了
Yeah. And I spilled the rest
coming down the water tower.
‎呃…水塔？搞什么？
The… water tower? What the hell?
‎艾瑞克 我来处理 水塔？搞什么？
Eric, let me handle this.
The water tower? What the hell?
‎这才是我喜欢的焰火
Now, this is my kind of fireworks.
‎对 水塔
Yes, the water tower.
‎我玩得很开心 我还想继续
And I had a great time
and I don't want it to end.
‎我知道你们会不高兴
So I know you're not
gonna like me saying this,
‎但…我想留在点域镇过暑假
but… I want to stay in Point Place
for the summer.
‎这是我的生活
‎我不想过得这么没意思
This is my life,
and I'm done letting it suck.
‎-莉亚
‎-对 你上
-Leia.
-Yeah, go.
‎别憋着 亲 全面出击
Just unload, baby. Both barrels. Go.
‎-你很有胆量 我很佩服
‎-啥？
-That took courage. I'm impressed.
-What?!
‎这主意太荒谬了
Th-This is a ridiculous idea.
‎-莉亚
‎-妈 你上 说说她
-Leia.
-Mom, just go, preach.
‎如果你想留下来 我们当然欢迎
You are welcome to stay here
if that's what you want.
‎我的天！什么情况？
Oh my God! What's happening?
‎凯蒂
Kitty.
‎我想这就是我们想要的
I guess that's what we want.
‎老爸 你们总是说
Dad, you guys always talk about
‎小时候跟朋友在一起有多开心
the amazing times
you had with your friends.
‎我也想要 我也想开心
I want that. I want amazing.
‎听着 伙计 短短一天之内
Listen, pal. In the space of one day,
‎你穿了洞 喝了酒 现在又…这么嘚瑟
you've gotten pierced, you've gotten beer,
and you've gotten
‎你穿了洞 喝了酒 现在又…这么嘚瑟
extremely snippy.
‎你变得我都不认识了
You've turned into someone
that I don't know anymore.
‎不行 知道吗？想都别想
So no. You know what? You can forget it.
‎我就知道你会这样
I knew you were gonna be like this.
‎明天我不会上那辆车 你强迫不了我
I'm not getting in that car tomorrow!
You can't make me!
‎你给我乖乖上车 不然我打你屁股
Oh, you're getting in that car
or my foot is getting in your ass!
‎-哦 艾瑞克
‎-太逊了
-Oh, Eric.
-So bad.
‎我现在骄傲到不行
I have never been prouder.
‎就好像看着你第一次打全垒打
It's like watching you hit
your first home run.
‎当然 如果你打过的话
If you had ever done that.
[soft guitar music playing]
[crickets chirping]
‎你没事吧？
You okay?
‎真不敢相信
I can't believe it.
‎我研究了一辈子《星球大战》
‎结果到了关键时刻
I study Star Wars my entire life,
and in my moment of truth,
‎我却变成了自己的邪恶老爸
I turn into my evil father.
‎我考虑过了
I've thought about it.
‎莉亚留下来也不会太离谱
‎毕竟你父母会照看她
Leia staying isn't the craziest idea.
Your parents can watch her.
‎70年代 咱们不也一起在这里吗？
Were you not here with me in the '70s?
‎让他们看孩子可不靠谱
They are not the best watchers.
‎她是好孩子
She's a great kid.
‎是啊 我知道
Yeah, I know.
‎我们可以相信她
We can trust her.
‎我知道
I know.
‎所以呢？
So what, then?
‎我只是…
I just…
‎她不再需要我了 这让我受不了
I mean, I can't stand this feeling.
She doesn't need me anymore.
‎我是说 她一直是我的小伙伴
‎而现在却变得像是…
I mean, she was my little buddy,
and now she's like
‎陌生人
a stranger.
‎她不是陌生人 她只是…长大了
She's not a stranger.
She's just… growing up.
‎我不喜欢
I don't like it.
‎什么？可你那么擅长隐藏自己的感情
What? But you're so good
at hiding your emotions.
[both chuckle]
‎没事的 艾瑞克
Eric, it's gonna be okay.
‎你父母给了我们空间
‎让我们找到彼此 共度人生
We have our whole lives
‎你父母给了我们空间
‎让我们找到彼此 共度人生
because your parents
gave us the space to find each other.
‎真的吗？
Really?
‎你家就距离六米远
‎咱俩肯定会找到彼此
You lived 20 feet away. I'm pretty sure
we would have found each other.
[soft guitar music playing]
‎嘿
Hey.
‎干嘛？
What?
‎-你的鼻环呢？
‎-那就是一块磁铁
-Oh, what happened to the nose ring?
-It was a magnet.
‎我打了个喷嚏 它掉进下水道了
I sneezed and it went down the drain.
Ah.
‎哎呀 好可惜
Well, I'm… I'm heartbroken.
‎我在你这么大的时候
‎我和朋友们成天宅在这间地下室
Back when I was your age,
‎我在你这么大的时候
‎我和朋友们成天宅在这间地下室
my friends and I pretty much
lived down in this basement.
‎我们一起打发时间 听音乐
‎做些…其他事情
We'd kill time, listen to music,
do… other things.
‎坐在那边的楼梯上 我爱上了你妈妈
Sitting on those stairs right there
when I fell in love with your mom.
‎老天 你们还在楼梯上做过？
Oh God. Did you do it on those stairs too?
‎没有
No.
‎听着 我考虑过了…
Look, I've been thinking about it, and…
‎你可以留下…过暑假
You should stay… for the summer.
‎-你说真的吗？
‎-对
-Are you for real?
-Yeah.
‎要说谁值得拥有…快乐 那就是你
If anyone deserves some… amazing,
it's you.
‎我的天 谢谢爸爸
‎很抱歉 我刚才那么犯浑
Oh my God, Dad. Thank you.
Sorry I was kind of a jerk.
‎没想到 在这方面 你还挺厉害的
Well, you were
surprisingly good at it. [chuckles]
‎要知道…
But, you know, you're…
‎你做什么都厉害
You're good at everything.
‎我会想你的 伙计
I'll miss you, pal.
‎我很爱你 知道吗？
I love you so much, okay?
[sighs softly]
‎你在闻我的头发吗？
Are you smelling my hair?
‎没有
No.
‎那也太诡异了
'Cause that would be weird.
‎好了
[sniffs] Okay.
[soft rock music playing]
‎记住 我们的电话号码没变 好吗？
So just remember
our phone number hasn't changed, okay?
‎别担心 亲爱的 我能搞定
Don't worry, honey. I got it.
‎还是能搞定
Again.
‎好的 亲爱的
Okay, babe.
‎我的宝贝儿子
My baby boy.
‎妈
Oh, uh… Mom.
Shh!
‎我在听你的心跳
I'm listening to your heartbeat.
‎好吧 行了
Look. Okay.
[Donna coos]
‎爱你哟 莉莉
Love you, Le-Le.
‎再见 妈妈
Bye, Mom.
‎别担心 我们会玩得很开心的
Don't worry. We're gonna have fun.
‎你清理过烤箱吗？
You ever cleaned an oven?
‎祝你好运
Good luck.
‎还有一件事 莉亚 这事…真的很重要
And one more thing, Leia.
This one's… really important.
‎你跟你的新朋友
‎尽量多去爷爷的地下室
With your new friends, I want you
to hang out in Grandpa's basement
‎尽量在那里玩
as much as possible.
‎不 不可能
No. Uh-uh. No way.
‎对她来说 那里最安全
It is the safest place for her.
‎没错 妈妈 就是这样
That's right, Mom. That's so right.
‎儿子 你够狠
Nicely played, son.
‎名师出高徒嘛
I learned from the best.
‎没人喜欢马屁精
Nobody likes an ass-kisser.
‎我也爱你 老爸
I love you too, Dad.
‎再见 妈
Bye, Mom.
‎她叫“妈”了
She said "Mom."
‎我赢了
I win.
‎所以说嘛 别跟行家叫板
That's why you don't mess with a pro.
[rock music playing]
‎我得列张购物清单
Well, I have to make a shopping list.
‎孩子们肯定要吃零食
The kids are gonna want snacks.
‎凯蒂 别给他们准备吃的
Don't feed them, Kitty.
‎后面就收不住了
That's how it started the first time.
‎嗨 我和朋友们要去湖边
Hey. Me and my friends
are going up to the lake.
‎等一下
[Red] Hold on.
‎-你是谁？
‎-我是杰伊
-Who are you?
-I'm Jay.
‎-杰伊凯尔索
‎-不
-Jay Kelso.
-No!
Uh-uh!
‎不行
No way!
‎呛爆啦！
Buuuurn!
Ahh!
‎见到我儿子了吧？瞅瞅这小子
See you met my boy here, huh?
Look at this guy. Look at him.
‎继承了他爹的长相和他妈的脑子
Look, he's got his dad's looks
and his mom's brains.
‎去年的优等生
Straight A's last year.
‎老天爷 人类在进化
Sweet Lord, it's evolving.
[Kelso chuckles]
‎你们一起好好玩儿 知道吗？
Hey, you kids. You have fun now, okay?
‎如果要从悬崖往下跳 最好光着身子
Oh, and if you jump off that cliff,
do it naked.
‎好吗？如果入水角度合适的话
Okay? 'Cause when you hit the water
at the right angle,
‎感觉就像打炮
it's like doing it with a lake.
‎你好 麦克尔
Hello, Michael.
‎嘿 妹子
Hey, girl.
[Kitty giggles]
Beautiful! [yells, laughs]
[Kitty laughs]
‎诶哟 这感觉…有年代 还暖烘烘的
-Well, that felt… toned and warm.
-[Kelso] Oh.
‎我说 雷德
So, Red,
‎我们得聊聊你孙女对我儿子的企图
we need to talk about your granddaughter's
intentions with my boy.
‎没有 逗你玩呢 来抱一个
No, I'm just kidding ya.
Come on. Let's hug it out.
‎你觉得呢？
What do you think?
‎走啦 麦克尔！
Michael, let's go!
‎嗨 凯蒂
Hi, Kitty.
‎该死 杰姬 你就让我享受一会行吗？
Damn, Jackie, will you just
give me a minute to enjoy this?
‎我的天啊
Oh my God.
‎雷德额头上的血管都快爆了
The vein on Red's forehead
is about to explode.
‎真恶心 我可不想
‎让老头的血溅在我的婚礼套服上
Gross! I don't want old guy blood
all over my wedding outfit.
‎你俩要结婚了？
You're getting married?
‎再婚
Remarried.
‎-对 这是我们第二次再婚
‎-嗯哼
-Yeah, it's our second remarriage.
-Mm-hmm.
‎-这次会坚持下去 对吧？
‎-对
-This one's gonna stick, right?
-Yeah.
‎杰姬
Jackie.
‎亲 穿白色哇？
White, honey?
‎真的吗？
Really?
‎劳动节还没过呢
It's before Labor Day.
‎如果人们以为我们是初婚
‎我们收到的礼物会更好
And, if people think it's our first time,
we'll get better gifts.
‎顺便说一句 我们在
‎布鲁明戴尔百货注册了 我很挑剔哦
Oh! FYI, we're registered
at Bloomingdale's,
‎顺便说一句 我们在
‎布鲁明戴尔百货注册了 我很挑剔哦
and I will judge.
‎-走啦 麦克尔！
‎-老天爷！
-Let's go, Michael!
-Oh God!
[Kitty exclaims, giggles]
[chuckles]
‎那我们就好好利用吧
Well, let's just make the best of it.
‎我要去趟市场
I am heading to the market
‎买点“菲乐多” “立体脆” “多力多滋”
‎那些零食全都要
'cause I'm going to get Fritos,
Tostitos, Doritos. All the "itos."
‎我卷土重来了 宝贝
I am back, baby!
‎混蛋
Son of a bitch.
[rock music playing]
‎好了 孩子们 地下室归你们了
Okay, kids, the basement is all yours.
‎开着灯 穿着衣服 不许跳舞
Lights on, shirts on, and no dancing.
[Leia laughs]
‎不许跳舞
‎你们像是在演《浑身是劲》
No dancing.
You're like the guy from Footloose.
‎伙计们 不许跳舞
No dancing, you guys.
‎亲爱的 这里放得下三间你家地下室
Babe, you can fit three of your basements
in this basement.
‎听着就费力 妮可
That sounds like a lot of work, Nik.
‎我们就用这个地下室吧
Let's just use this basement.
‎这些旧家具多棒啊？
Don't you love all this old furniture?
‎是的 来几个抱枕
‎再把破伤风针打了就圆满了
Yeah, all we need are some throw pillows
and a tetanus shot.
‎福尔曼夫人 您家真温馨好客
Mrs. Forman, your home is so warm
and inviting.
‎我很期待在这里过暑假
I mean, I can't wait to spend
all summer inside of it. [chuckles]
‎你什么毛病？
What is wrong with you?
‎总之…好了
Anyway… Okay.
‎如果你们觉得无聊
‎我找到些你爸的旧唱片和游戏
Now, if you kids get bored, I found
some old records and games of your dad's,
‎还有一些他不愿让我发现的杂志
and a few magazines
that I don't think he wanted me to see,
‎但我已经扔了
but I got rid of them.
‎她们都是红头发
They were all redheads.
‎他有喜欢的类型
[scoffs] He sure has a type!
‎总之 你们好好玩
Anyhoo, you guys have fun.
‎哇 这东西肯定比任天堂还古早
Whoa, this must be from a Nintendo Zero.
‎不是吧
No way.
‎你奶奶给了我们好东西
Your grandma just hooked us up.
‎-不是吧
‎-必须的
-No way.
-Hell yeah.
‎必须的
Totally.
[laughs]
‎是什么呀？
What is it?
‎最精彩的夏天
Best summer ever!
[all laughing]
‎算我一个
Sign me up!
‎但说真的 是什么呀？
But seriously, what is it?
[rock music playing]
‎一 二 三 四
One, two, three, four!
‎现在是夏天 我们好好开心一下吧
‎咱应该随心所欲做想做的事 对吧？
It's the summer. Let's have fun.
We should do whatever we want. Right?
‎错
Wrong.
‎-你知道我想要什么吗？
‎-别说杰伊
-[Leia] You know what I want?
-Don't say Jay.
‎杰伊
Jay.
‎-你被禁止进入本宅了 出去
‎-不！
-You are banned from this house. Get out.
-No!
‎唐娜 我是凯蒂 你女儿要跟人上床了
Donna, it's Kitty!
Your daughter is about to have sex!
‎她在哪里？
Where is she?
‎等等 所以爸爸
‎并不像他自己说得那么八面玲珑？
Wait, so Dad wasn't as smooth
as he says he was?
‎只能说你的存在是种幸运
Let's just say you're lucky you exist.
‎你们是谁吼了我们家孩子？
Hey, which one of you yelled at my kids?
‎我不知道你的孩子是谁
‎但是他们活该
I don't know which ones are yours,
but they deserved it.
‎他们是格温和内特 另外谢谢
That's Gwen and Nate, and thanks.
‎他在我肚子待了十个月
I was pregnant with him for ten months.
‎医生说没什么问题 但我觉得有问题
The doctor said it was okay,
but I don't think it was.
‎你好像对我的润唇膏过敏
I think you might be having
a reaction to one of my Lip Smackers.
‎真的吗？
Really?
‎-我想向你奶奶出柜
‎-我明天有个面试
-I want to come out to your grandmother.
-I have an interview tomorrow.
‎-你有什么推荐信吗？
‎-我的老板们都很爱我
-[Nikki] Do you have any references?
-Oh, my bosses all loved me.
‎但他们都死了
But they are dead.
[rock music continues]
‎我是同志！
[Ozzie] I'm gaaaay!
‎（菲丝轩）
‎我说 回见您呐
I said, good day.
[all cheering]
[rock music playing]
‎字幕翻译：Zeo Niu